Previously on "The Ark"...
Lieutenant Brice?
It's me, Dr. Morozov.
You really think
they're down there?
Only one way to find out.
We have to get a signal
to "Ark 1."
Slide under the door first.
I've got to read
all about you.
I really wished
you'd let this go.
Yes! It sent.
You have to fix me.
What the hell?
So the message arrived with
a looping distress signal.
A home beacon--
it's coming from Ross.
Can you pinpoint
its location on the planet?
We'd have to be
much closer for that.
I want to believe this
as much as you do, Ava,
but I saw Brice die
with my own eyes.
I don't see how
it could be him.
The signal came on
a secure GSA frequency
embedded with
Brice's ID number.
It would take
someone with access
to proprietary GSA passwords
and information to fake it.
So even if it's not James--
Someone is asking for help.
We leave in an hour.
- I'm coming with you.
Damn straight you are.
You're giving him blood?
His blood pressure
dropped last night.
He has some internal bleeding.
I'm giving him clotting agents.
Are you going somewhere?
"Ark 1" needs me,
and, to be honest,
I need some space.
Can we talk about it?
Um, not right now.
"Ark 1" leaves in 45 minutes.
Okay.
Look, the time away,
it'll do us some good.
I can clear my head up there.
I understand.
We're both just
doing our best.
Promise me you'll be
careful out there, okay?
Yeah.
Hey.
Let's talk when I get back.
I'll be here.
Admiral Hammond knows Ross
better than we do,
but I can't raise him on comms,
and we don't have time
to wait for him.
If I find him before
you're out of range,
I'll put him on
with you for guidance.
Thank you.
Are you sure
you don't want me to come?
Stay with Angus.
Enjoy your time together.
Thanks.
And the adjustments
I made to the shields
will give you more time
in Ross's solar storms.
Just remember to reroute
no more than 10%
of the gravitons
to "Ark 1's" exterior.
For more power, you can--
- Alicia, don't worry.
I've got it.
- Okay.
Good luck.
I hope you find Brice.
Thanks.
Dr. Marsh.
Clear.
Time of death, 10:45.
So once Kelly and I
got out of the chamber,
there were, like,
10 of them waiting for us.
Then Alicia scared
them off with her WD.
We all feared the worst.
How well did you see them?
Well enough to see
they were human.
They're not human.
They definitely
looked like it.
Like our John Doe?
I think he was one of them.
He was wearing Angus's clothes.
Unless all ten of them
stowed away on one
or more of our ships, got here,
and then somehow built
a giant underground complex
in a few weeks,
they're not human,
and to think so is idiotic.
What Mr. Trust
is trying to say,
in his usual sweet way,
is that evolving here
to be identical to us--
Except their ears
and vocal cords.
Yes, even with
those differences,
the odds of that sort
of parallel evolution
are astronomical.
- But not zero.
And this isn't the first thing
we've seen on Homebase
that kind of seems like it.
- Such as?
The trees.
They look like Earth trees.
And, I mean, I haven't had
a chance to test the dead bird
we found yet since
we got snatched and all,
but it sure looked like
a Eurasian blackbird.
So test it.
Test everything.
I think you'll find
it's as much about Earth
as those cave creatures.
In the meantime, whoever--
whatever these people are,
they're obviously intelligent.
We should try and
communicate with them,
see if we can get some answers.
- I don't agree.
We don't know what they had
planned for Angus and Kelly,
and one of them already
put our sheriff
in critical condition
in Med Bay.
Has anyone studied
the garments
they had Angus dressed in?
They appear to be
made from a fabric
derived from local vegetation.
Which might be
Earth vegetation.
Or might not.
Listen, just let me
go back out there
and collect fresh plant
and tree samples,
perform a full analysis
DNA spectroscopy.
You want to go back
to the forest
where we just rescued
you and Kelly from?
We can send
an armed security officer
to accompany you.
- I vote against it.
It's too risky.
Avega?
I think we should
let him look further,
but limited to daylight hours.
I guess I'm outvoted.
If you insist on going back,
please be careful out there.
I'm going too.
I'm not letting Angus
out of my sight.
Ms. Ilic,
please report to Med Bay.
Excuse me.
Oh, Mr. Trust,
we could really
use your knowledge out there.
I think not.
If you'd excuse me.
I hear lunch
is very good today.
Last I heard, he was stable.
He went into cardiac arrest.
I tried to save him,
but I couldn't.
I'm sorry.
- I don't trust you, Marsh.
First Kabir tells me
Milan was abusive.
Next thing I know,
he dies under your care.
No doctor wants
to lose a patient,
no matter who they are.
I know he meant a lot to you.
I'm very sorry.
This isn't over.
Hey, you see those stolons?
The narrow blades
folded at the midrib?
Pointed tips like a monocot.
We might have something here.
What's it look like?
Poaceae maybe?
Can you imagine if it was
a match for a species on Earth?
Like--like,
what would that even mean?
What?
I'm being serious.
I just missed you,
that's all.
Ah.
Thank you.
Alicia?
Is that Admiral Hammond?
Okay.
Preparing to disengage FTL.
Stand by, Eva.
In three, two, one.
Shields activated.
Here we are again.
- Eva?
- Stand by.
Eva?
We're good now.
Shields will hold
for ten hours.
Okay.
10 hours of shields,
and, uh, only 92 minutes
until the sun sets
on the Ross colony.
We need to move fast.
- EVA suits?
Didn't need them last time,
and it's hot as hell
down there.
All right, no EVA suits.
Dr. Kabir, meet us
in the shuttle dock.
Make sure your straps
are tight.
This will get bumpy.
Once we're through,
let's track the distress signal
and touch down near its source.
- You mean Brice.
- Uh, hopefully.
We need to get him and get back
in the shuttle before sunset.
Looks like it might be
coming from the colony.
Heading in that direction.
Signal's getting stronger.
Looks like someone
dropped a bomb on it.
This is where you were
attacked by those creatures?
Yeah.
They were attacking
the building when we left.
I guess they finished the job.
No one could survive
in there.
Yeah, which means no one
can send a signal from there.
Look, we're honing in
on the signal.
Oh, yeah, that's far away
from the structures.
What is that?
The noise from
the solar flare.
Do you mind, Captain?
- Please.
There.
- Should I adjust course?
15 degrees right,
6 kilometers out.
Copy.
Looks like it's somewhere
inside that forest.
I don't see any structures.
There's no indication of any.
Beacon is 2.1 kilometers in.
Okay.
Close enough if we hurry.
Set down there
by the tree line.
We'll hoof it from there.
Well, too bad Angus
isn't here.
These trees are the same
as the ones on Homebase.
Which makes no sense.
Do we need to be worried
about those creatures
coming out for a snack?
I'm not reading
any heat signatures.
I think we're clear.
- Okay. Everyone ready?
Eva?
- Are you okay, Eva?
Yeah.
Oh.
Uh, I guess
I'm a little nervous.
The tracker startled me.
- Understandable.
Hey, no matter what,
we're here for you, okay?
Yeah.
Thank you.
All right, we have 26 minutes
until we have to turn back.
Let's be smart with our time.
Is that--
Completely identical
to the one on Homebase?
Yeah, does anyone
have a good explanation
for two identical structures
on planets
32 light years apart?
- That's not all.
On Homebase, Angus's WD could
barely get through the walls.
How did we receive
Brice's signal from here?
It seems like a trap.
Why else would the door
just be propped open?
A trap by who?
Well, maybe this planet has
its own people living in caves?
We don't want
to end up locked
in there like Angus and Kelly.
Well, we can't just
leave James in there.
If he's in there.
Look, I'm going in
with or without you--
Hold on!
Hold on.
No one's going rogue.
Kimi, what do you think?
We're armed.
I say we go in.
I agree.
Eva and I will take lead.
Kimi, watch our six.
Ian, cover our flanks.
Sanji, stay by me.
- Mm-hmm.
Got it.
It looks just like the inside
of the Homebase tunnel.
But how?
Better question is,
who built it?
This way.
We're getting close.
Oh.
It's coming from
the other side of this wall.
Okay, everyone, spread out.
See if you can find
some way in,
uh, some kind of door
or opening--
Everyone, back!
Kimi, stand guard.
Oh, God.
Is he even alive?
Please say he's alive.
Get him free, now!
Eva, come on!
Eva.
Wait.
Get this.
You got this.
Easy.
It's okay.
Dr. Marsh's
medical report ruled
that Hammond died
of a stab wound
caused by a large blade.
Marsh,
is he the best we can do
for a medical examiner?
I am very, very sorry
about Sheriff Petrovic--
I am--
but Marsh is a good doctor.
- Agree to disagree.
- Hm.
Any other noteworthy findings?
The woods were
just a dump site.
Hammond was murdered elsewhere
and then dragged to where
he was discovered.
Ah.
Am I alone in suspecting
these people,
or whatever they are,
in the caves?
The thought
did cross my mind.
Let's gather all the facts
before we draw any conclusions.
There's no murder weapon yet,
but a security detail
is combing the area now.
We appreciate you taking
the lead on this, Felix.
You all right, Dr. Marsh?
It never gets easier
to lose a patient.
Even that one?
What's that supposed to mean?
Well, I noticed you
and Dr. Kabir's relationship
is sort of on the rocks.
We have hit a rough spot,
yes,
but what does that have to do
with that patient?
I looked him up.
Sheriff Petrovic was
Dr. Kabir's ex-husband.
Did you know that?
- You looked him up?
- I was curious.
- How is that your business?
I suppose it's not.
Is that what caused
this rough spot?
Why do you have
so many questions, Jelena?
I was just wondering
if Dr. Kabir's
former relationship
had anything to do
with you hesitating
when he coded.
I didn't hesitate.
I had to check
the readings to decide
the proper course of action.
Okay.
Are you accusing me
of something?
No, not at all.
Jelena...
I'm asking you as a friend,
please use discretion
when discussing this
with anyone else.
Of course.
Any luck pulling the data
from Hammond's WD?
No.
The killer must have wiped it,
along with the remote backups.
Doesn't sound like
a person from the caves.
I doubt they could use
our tech.
Thank you for trying.
- You're welcome.
But I was thinking,
and I realized,
WDs aren't the only thing
that leave a digital footprint.
I checked Hammond's
database activity.
Without admin codes, I had to
bypass encryption algorithms.
I thought it would
be way harder, but--
- You found something.
- Sorry, yeah.
Based on Admiral Hammond's
searches,
it seemed like he was
super interested in Ves.
Like, kind of obsessed.
- Ves? Ves Ilic?
- Yeah.
It seemed like
he was trying to find out
everything he could about her.
Here.
Take a look.
What's that missing text?
Class 3 GSA redactions.
Why? Who is she?
I'm not sure yet.
In the meantime,
do not share this with anyone.
Of course.
We don't have
much time to waste
before she covers her tracks.
Well, try.
Try to find someone willing
to share with either of them.
Okay, bye. Thanks for calling.
Um, everything all right?
Marital spat.
Wife wants husband to move out,
but we don't have anywhere else
for him to move in.
How can I help you?
Yes, it's come
to my attention
that Admiral Hammond had taken
quite an interest in you.
Really?
You're joking.
Any idea why?
Well, he seemed to be
attracted to me.
It was kind of flattering.
I think it's more than that.
How so?
He was looking
at your records.
That's odd.
He must have been
quite bored with them.
Hmm.
You didn't have
any previous relationship?
No.
I just met the man.
You were aboard
the first Ark that arrived
here on Trappist, correct?
- Yes.
And what does that have to do
with Admiral Hammond?
I'm just doing
my due diligence.
Ah.
Well, I appreciate that.
I'm always available if
you have additional questions.
Thank you for your time.
We found something!
Mr. Strickland,
is that your sword?
Is someone there?
But you don't seem
to have any wounds.
I don't understand.
I guess I was
pretty bad off, eh?
You have no idea.
That's impossible.
I--I saw you die.
You were torn apart.
- It was Doc.
She nursed me back to health.
- Doc Morozov?
Aye.
Yeah, she saved my life.
Not one stitch, one scar.
Wait, how do we even know
this is Brice?
What the hell kind
of question is that?
What's your favorite scotch?
I hate scotch.
Yeah, it's him.
James, do you know
how you got here?
Uh, I don't--I don't know.
Where am I?
An underground cave on Ross.
What's the last thing
you remember?
I was in one of
the "Ark 4" structures.
Everything went dark,
and then I just--
I woke up here.
You were in "Ark 4"
structures?
Yeah, of course.
Where else can
we send a signal?
- We?
- Yes, me and Doc.
We--she got injured.
Listen, we need to go.
We need to go.
We need to help her now.
- James, Morozov is dead.
Shit.
Oh, shit.
Was it the Raiders?
- Raiders?
Aye, the Raiders.
They--they came in.
They were heavily armed.
They shot her.
There weren't any other ships
in orbit when we arrived.
Look, I know what I saw, okay?
We're wasting time.
We need to go.
We need to go now, okay?
- James, Doc is dead.
You and I both saw her die.
I would remember that, okay?
No, I am sorry,
James, but I do.
I saw her die.
Well, you said
you saw me die as well.
And I'm right here, aren't I?
- Okay.
All right, look,
where did you see her last?
The "Ark 4" comms array.
We're running out of time.
Kimi, we might need
a hand in here.
Kimi?
Garnet to Kimi, do you copy?
Ian, let's go find her.
Eva, Dr. Kabir,
get him hydrated
and ready to move out.
- Yeah.
What would make her
wander off?
She wouldn't.
In the tunnels on Homebase,
did the walls open
in the same way?
Sharon?
Sharon!
Thanks for coming to get me.
What was I supposed to do?
You missed our call.
- Sharon's gone!
- What?
She disappeared.
She was right beside me,
and she disappeared.
- Let's go find her.
- Yeah.
Sharon!
Stay close, all right?
Kimi?
Don't take your eyes
off each other, all right,
not even for a second.
That's all it takes.
She couldn't have gone far.
There are probably
other rooms
like the one we found you in.
Yeah, but the trouble
is finding them.
Sharon!
Sharon, is that you?
- Where's Kabir?
She was right there.
Sanji!
- No.
- Eva.
Hold on.
- No!
No!
Don't let go!
Eva!
Did you just see
what I just saw?
Because my sense of reality
is really cocked up right now.
Yeah, yeah, if you saw
that rock wall
suck Eva into it,
then yeah, I saw it.
Yeah, I did, but that's--
that's totally
frickin' crazy, right?
Look, there has to be
a seam or something
that we can pry open.
Can you see anything?
Mate, there's nothing.
I've got nothing.
Damn it.
I wonder why
we weren't taken.
Look, the only difference
I can think is that we're men.
Right, it's only the women
who've been taken.
Right?
- Yeah, why would that be?
I don't know, mate!
All right, look,
maybe if they can hear us,
they can--they can let us in
from the other side.
Yeah? Yeah.
Sharon!
Sharon, can you hear us?
- Eva!
Kimi!
Dr. Kabir!
Ian, shine your light here.
Look.
Something's moving
inside of these.
Oh, don't--
don't touch it.
Maybe if we follow it,
it might lead us somewhere.
Oh, Brice, look at this.
It looks different.
Yeah, like it's been
touched a lot.
Come on.
- Oh, no.
What?
It's gonna be
getting dark outside.
We should have left already.
- Oh, God.
Yes!
Come on.
- Eva! Eva!
- Sharon.
Let go!
Okay, I've got you.
Come here.
Okay. Come on. okay.
- Can you breathe?
- Yeah.
You okay?
Sanji!
Come on.
Easy, all right.
Hey, you're okay.
Uh, guys.
- Brice is alive?
- Long story.
Let's get the hell
out of here.
Do me a favor, everyone.
Stay away from the walls.
What did you guys see when
you went through the walls?
It all happened so fast.
As far as I could tell,
the walls swallowed me
and spit me into
that web thing in one motion.
- Same here.
By the time I was in,
my arms were already pinned.
I've never felt
more helpless.
- Why is it doing this?
- I don't know.
But I don't want
to give this place
another chance to trap us.
We need to move faster.
We're barely gonna
beat the sun.
Go! Go!
Go, go, go, go!
Sharon, what about Doc?
We'll check from above!
Come on!
- Go, go, go!
What the hell?
No.
Look, me and Doc,
we were just down there.
You said you sent
the signal from there.
Yeah, from the comms array.
But it's the last thing
I remember doing.
James, we tracked that signal
to the underground room
where we found you.
The signal came
from room you were in.
Your WD was wired
into the wall somehow.
Got a visual ahead.
No.
Can you get
close on her face?
Turn it off.
Sorry.
There's no way she could
survive those injuries.
So she couldn't have
been with you, James.
I'm sorry.
We received Marsh's
forensic report.
The blood on the sword
was Hammond's,
but the only fingerprints
found were yours.
Well,
of course my fingerprints
were on it.
It's my sword.
I'm sorry.
I'm not used to being on
this side of the situation.
Because you're
not a murderer.
Ms. Fowler, please.
You don't know him.
Felix is not a murderer.
Ms. Fowler,
we allowed you to come with us
under the agreement
that you do as we say.
I'm only going to ask you
this once, Felix.
Did you do this?
Of course not.
I barely knew Admiral Hammond,
let alone had a reason
to kill him.
I'll get to the bottom
of this.
What about my daughter?
That's why I came,
to offer to take care of her
for as long as you need.
Thank you.
Are you sure she's who you
want watching over your child?
We can make other arrangements.
Whoever's setting me up
could come for Katheryn.
Kelly can protect her.
As you wish.
Zed...
I am innocent.
I believe you.
I'll bring Katheryn
to visit every day.
Well?
What did those
web things do to us?
Nothing to the three
of you or me,
at least not that I can see.
Just a tiny scar from
that hole behind our ears
where that tube was attached
to all of us.
And the tube
didn't do anything?
Not to us,
at least not that I can find.
What about Brice?
Yeah, what about Brice?
You, sir, are like
some kind of frickin' miracle.
There are no signs of trauma,
no scars, nothing.
You're healthy as a horse.
But you saw
the life sign data
when we left Ross
the first time.
He was dead.
- I know.
I saw the recording
of the attack too.
He should, at the very least,
have scars all over his body.
Is there any chance
he's one of us?
A clone?
No.
I checked his DNA.
He's James Brice Prime.
Guys, I am telling you,
it seemed like
Doc was there, right?
And she was the one
who fixed me up.
James, you saw her body,
or what was left of it.
Even if she was alive
and she had
the best surgery facility...
- No.
Ever built
and a staff of experts,
she couldn't have healed you
to this extent.
Okay, okay.
But then what about
the Raiders, right?
Were they at least real?
I'm afraid it was
all in your head, James.
But it's possible
that thing going in
behind your ear
induced vivid dreams.
No, no.
Look, it was too real.
- I get it, believe me.
Dreams can feel
pretty bloody real.
Okay, so you think
that the webbing
that was attached to him
healed him?
I don't know what else
it could be.
But that doesn't explain
why we were caught in it.
- Yeah, or why I wasn't.
- We didn't need healing.
And we didn't dream
or hallucinate
when we were in them.
Maybe because we never
lost consciousness.
Well, I--
I won't pretend
I understand any of it,
but I'm really glad
you're back among the living.
Did you miss me, Sharon?
Mm.
Come on.
Oh, there is
one more weird thing.
When Lieutenant Brice
left "Ark 1,"
he didn't have an appendix.
Yeah, I got it taken out
in college.
I know.
I saw it on your charts.
But guess what?
Now you have a healthy,
intact appendix.
- I'm sorry, what?
- What?
- It's been way too long.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
We've got a lot
of catching up to do.
Really?
Here?
Right here?
Well, the next shift
won't come in for an hour,
unless you want to wait.
No.
Hell, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Just ignore it.
- It's the genomic sequencer.
- It can wait.
Are you serious right now?
- I'm sorry.
It's the results of
our first few samples.
You're not
the least bit curious?
Yeah, but at
this very moment--
Okay. I'm just--
I'm just gonna mute it.
I'm just gonna mute it, okay?
Oh! Oh, man!
- What?
The sequencer analyzed
the grass sample--
Cynodon dactylon.
It's Bermuda grass.
You mean it's
like Bermuda grass.
No, it's--
it's Bermuda grass.
It was all over Earth.
- Well, what about the bird?
Turdus merula,
Eurasian blackbird.
And the tree?
Common black poplar.
How is that possible?
Come to bed, James.
I'm still waiting for you
to fix me...
Buddy.
- James?
- Huh?
Are you sure you're okay?
Um...
Yeah, no, I'm fine.
Yeah.
Well, you still
haven't received
a proper homecoming yet.